Stefon Simmons

FRONTEND ENGINEER









stefonsimmons 1@gmail.com

stefonsimmons.me

github.com/StefonSimmons

linkedin.com/in/StefonSimmons

I'm a self-motivated and inquisitive teacher, frontend React.js developer, and artist with over 7 years working in higher education and 15 years as a recording artist. My creativity as an artist and organization as an administrator feed greatly into my passion for software programming. Currently, I am seeking to work with people and companies who, like myself, are determined to learn and develop products/services as well as invest in people. I consistently contribute strong problem-solving and interpersonal skills to my work and rely on my adaptive mindset for designing new processes and technology to production.

Skills & Abilities

| React.js | Hugo | Axios |
|-------------------|----------------------------------|----------------|
| JavaScript | HTML5 & CSS3 / Sass | Jest Testing |
| Styled Components | Interactive design / prototyping | Git and GitHub |

Experience

TEACHING ASSISTANT - SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | JULY 2020 - PRESENT

- · Teach HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Ruby on Rails, SQL and noSQL, data structures, and algorithms to web developers
- · Debug code produced by a team of up to 20 web developers in a live online remote learning environment
- · Foster a results-driven community for web development that encourages well-documented and efficient production code

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING FELLOW

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | MARCH 2020 – JUNE 2020

- · Created, developed, and deployed to the cloud 4 responsive web apps within strict one-week due dates
- Leveraged fluent knowledge of HTML, CSS, and React to co-lead development of a full-stack web application within a large collaborative of UX Designers and Engineers
- · Dedicated over 800 hours in 3 months towards developing my skills in planning and deploying web applications

REGISTRAR / FRONTEND DEVELOPER / SQL SCRIPTING SPECIALIST

THE NEW YORK CONSERVATORY FOR DRAMATIC ARTS | NOVEMBER 2013 - MARCH 2020

- · Designed the student and faculty-facing student and faculty portal using HTML and in-line CSS aiding student enrollment
- Created a system that consolidates the time it takes to track and report attendance for an average annual enrollment of 270 students by using MS Excel formulas, Word, SQL Server and SQL Reporting tools
- · Resolved technical issues for students, faculty and staff to maintain production of services.

Web Applications

ROOM | HUGO, BOOTSTRAP, JAVASCRIPT, HTML, SASS

 Responsive CSS grid landing page w/ a Bootstrap carousel. My solution to a frontendmentor.io challenge. Deployed to AWS S3 cloud storage and CloudFront CDN. http://d3jqefpza7ezsc.cloudfront.net/

WILL-Do | REACT.JS, HTML, CSS, AIRTABLE, EXPRESS.JS

 Responsive to mobile and full CRUD task management app. Enriched with a custom drag and drop feature for prioritizing tasks. https://will-do.netlify.app/

NEUROSCIENTIST'S WEBSITE | REACT.JS, HTML, STYLED-COMPONENTS, EXPRESS, NODEMAILER

• Freelance project built using styled-components for color theming and CSS-in-JS component styling. Includes a custom slideshow for mobile views. https://www.ashleaamorgan.com/

Education

GENERAL ASSEMBLY, NEW YORK, NY

· Software Engineering | Certificate of Completion, June 2020

UDEMY

- · JAVASCRIPT ALGORITHMS AND DATA STRUCTURES MASTERCLASS | Certificate of Completion, In progress
- THE ULTIMATE MYSQL BOOTCAMP | Certificate of Completion, August 2019
- · MICROSOFT SQL FROM A TO Z | Certificate of Completion, July 2019

NORFOLK STATE UNIVERSITY, NORFOLK, VA

· Business Management | 3.64/4.0 (Magna Cum Laude) | Bachelor of Science, May 2012

Personal Interests

- · Singer, Songwriter, Performer, Recording Artist
- Painter
- · Theater Photographer